JOSE MANUEL SOLIS BULOS

Mexico | manuelbulos@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/manuelbulos | +528114818459

Professional Summary

Senior iOS Developer / Tech Lead with 7 years of industry experience specializing in developing and leading projects for top-tier companies. Successfully led the development of multiple high-impact applications, enhancing user engagement and performance.

Companies Worked For

- Samsung
- Jamf
- McCormick
- 1800 Flowers
- Procore
- Kik
- WKG Solutions
- Phonon X
- MediaLab.Al

Employment History

Procore

Senior iOS Engineer (Contract)

June 2023 - Current

- Owner of the Inspections Module inside the iOS app where I implemented new features, integrations, and improvements.
- Procore App: apps.apple.com/app/procore/id374930542

McCormick

Senior iOS Engineer (Contract)

August 2022 - August 2023

• Owner of the e-commerce shop module for the McCormick iOS app, building that module from scratch.

McCormick App: apps.apple.com/us/app/flavor-maker-by-mccormick/id1440670503

WKG Solutions

Tech Lead (macOS Engineer, Contract)

June 2022 - June 2023

- Led a team of 3 engineers
- Owner of 3 video editing apps for macOS using SwiftUI all developed from scratch.
- Patented one of those apps.

Phonon X

Senior iOS Engineer, Founding Member

September 2021 - September 2022

- Lead iOS developer for a new audio-based app flutter project from scratch.
- Notification content app extensions.
- Share extension Widgets.
- Siri extension
- Watch extension
- App Clip target
- Carbon Voice App: apps.apple.com/us/app/carbon-voice/id1567782769

1800 Flowers

Senior iOS Engineer (Contract)

October 2021 - February 2022

- Maintained and enhanced an existing eCommerce application using RxSwift.
- 1800 Flowers App: apps.apple.com/us/app/1800flowers/id457699767

Jamf

Senior iOS & macOS Developer (Contract)

July 2021 - November 2021

- Developed features to communicate and exchange keys between iOS and macOS using Bluetooth low energy connection with encrypted data.
- Jamf Solutions: <u>jamf.com/solutions/trusted-access</u>

Samsung **NEXT**

iOS Developer (Contract)

March 2020 - October 2021

- Owner of 2 Apps built from scratch, from the product proof of concept to the distribution.
- Actively contributed to the product roadmap, defining and proposing new features.
 Created and Presented product demos (features) to the CEO, Director, and Managers of the company.
- Helped the QA team with the integration of their automated tests.
- Evangelized for end-user experience improvements to enhance overall adoption rates, providing a more engaging product and a cleaner architecture not only for the app but also for the backend APIs.
- Samsung Health App: apps.apple.com/us/app/samsung-health/id1224541484

MediaLab.Al

iOS Engineer (Contract)

September 2019 - March 2020

- Updated and maintained native applications in Objective-C and Swift.
- Collaborated with project managers and coworkers to focus on performance and user experience.
- Work hand-in-hand with designers to build the UI for the new features of the existing apps.
- Kik App: apps.apple.com/us/app/kik-messaging-chat-app/id357218860
- Whisper App: whisper.sh

CloudSourcelT

iOS Developer

December 2017 - August 2019

- Developed and maintained various applications from scratch and performed quality assurance.
- CEMEX Today: apps.apple.com/us/app/cemex-today/id1299188257
- MyChristus: apps.apple.com/mx/app/mychristus/id1484091477
- TripSource: apps.apple.com/us/app/tripsource/id710472405
- Eventto: apps.apple.com/us/app/eventto-app/id1001673956
- Pasaporte NL: apps.apple.com/mx/app/pasaporte-nl/id1437667651
- Mi OXXO: apps.apple.com/mx/app/mi-oxxo/id1473147659

Grill on Box

iOS Developer

August 2017 - December 2017

• Focused on requirements analysis, technical documentation, and app development.

Fiverr

iOS Developer (Contract)

January 2017 - July 2017

- Rebuilt an Objective-C app in Swift and handled app distribution through Apple's Enterprise Program.
- Distributed app with Apple Enterprise Program, hosting the .ipa file on the client's server.
- Built an information-based offline application using Swift with Core Data, to store details about different locations (presenting coordinates on the native MapView component), and reminders.

Skills

Programming Languages:

• Swift (Advanced), Objective-C (Intermediate)

Development Tools & Frameworks:

• Xcode, SwiftUI (Advanced), UIKit (Advanced), SPM, Cocoapods, Carthage, Fastlane

Data Management:

· Core Data (Advanced), Realm

API Technologies:

REST (Advanced), GraphQL (Advanced), SOAP (Intermediate)

Development Practices:

 Human Interface Guidelines, Reactive Programming, Agile/Scrum, CI/CD (Continuous Integration and Continuous Distribution)

Testing & Debugging:

XCTest, XCUITest, Instruments

Version Control:

· Git, GitHub, Bitbucket

Education

Bachelor of Software Engineering Universidad TecMilenio, Monterrey, Nuevo Leon, Mexico

Graduated: 2018

Hobbies

- Music Production: Recording, mixing, and mastering with Logic Pro X and Ableton Live.
- Instruments: Guitar, Bass, Drums, Keyboard.